<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-12T14:33:18+00:00</updated><id>https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">realization</title><link href="https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/blog/2022/realization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="realization"/><published>2022-09-23T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-23T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/blog/2022/realization</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://whitesideofthesun.github.io/blog/2022/realization/"><![CDATA[<p>I turned twenty one last July. It was memorable.</p> <p>One thing that hits me the most is that I am aging. Like every other single human on earth.<br/> Confronting death doesn’t scare me a bit. It is the undigestable fact that I am going to run out of time to do/try whatever I want, which makes me feel uncomfortable. It feels simple yet astounding. Contrarily, I also do not wish to live forever, and if given an option I wouldn’t choose to be an eternal. I believe being a mortal is one of the things that makes our lives to be valued and cherished.</p> <p>The rational part of me knows that it is what it is and it is what it has been. But I still find it hard for me to accept.</p> <blockquote> <p>“You are young and life is long and there is time to kill today<br/> And then one day you find, ten years have got behind you<br/> No one told you when to run, you missed the starting gun”</p> </blockquote> <p>These above lines are from a song called Time by Pink Floyd.<br/> Probably my biggest fear is being able to relate to those in a decade or two.</p> <p>I am twenty one. I have never left my country. In Fact I barely have left my own state. I feel there is so much to learn and explore. While writing this, I listed down some of the things that I wanted to do in my life. You know, “bucket list”? Yes that thing. I hope in a couple of years some of the stuff in that are struck out and eventually everything.</p> <p>This little post is a mere attempt for me to process my thoughts so that I can look back. And I am sure I will cringe when I do.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="self"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I turned twenty one last July. It was memorable.]]></summary></entry></feed>